[Music]
hello everybody welcome to episode 39 of
ask abhijit this is the 39th live
episode
and today we discuss indian history i
take your questions about indian history
before we begin let me see who all is
there i can see himanshu mahesh patel
aryan
chandana narayan
barbaric
sharma polish thakur samia anand
abhishek srivastav
chavan devi
good evening good day everybody
it is great to be back with you all
so today we discuss indian history i
have
picked up a bunch of questions that you
have asked and let me get
right into it with question number one
this is by amlan
amlan says that a new research
found that
indus valley people
used proto-dravidian languages please
see this link and please take this
question and the link is provided so let
me let me uh
put the link on the screen and we will
discuss that
where is it here it is just a second i
will share that part of the screen
over here
just a minute
okay here it is
here it is
so this is an article that claims
okay let's see the title of the article
it says indus valley people spoke and
ancient dravidian language claims new
research
an independent researcher analyzed the
various evidence to suggest the
possibility
of the ancient civilization speaking the
ancestral dravidian language so the
article claims that this new research
suggests
the possibility
that this may be the case
it doesn't prove anything it is
suggesting a possibility
do you understand the difference between
proving something and suggesting a vague
possibility of something
that's a huge difference
suggesting the possibility of something
is not the same as proving something
there's an enormous difference between
the two this is merely one of the new
claims one of the millions of claims
that people have made
over the decades of having found the
clues that
end this mystery no
this simply suggests a certain
possibility of something let's go a
little bit further into it
independent researcher
analyzed numerous
archaeological linguistic and historical
evidence and found that the words for
relevant piri elephant piri piru in
bronze age mesopotamia were originally
borrowed from pilu
a proto-dravidian word for elephant
which was prevalent in the indus valley
civilization
my question is very simple
how does this person
know that know that this word pilu
was prevalent in the indus valley
civilization
have we been able to decipher the script
of the indus valley region of the
saraswati region have we deciphered the
script we have not been able to decipher
the script there are many claims of
people
claiming that they have deciphered it
none of these claims have stood
up to scrutiny so the script despite so
many different claims is not deciphered
as of today and if the script is not
deciphered how do we know what was the
word for elephant in this region
how do we know it
in the absence of the decipherment of
the script
how do we know what was the word for
elephant 5000 years ago in western india
we don't know it so on what basis
has this individual
decided that the word for elephant in
the indus valley region was pilu
there is no logical basis for this claim
this research is clearly nonsense
and my question is how does such garbage
research get published in reputed
journals
this is the problem
in
the research
in in the academic research that is
being done in indology and in the
history of ancient india these
nonsensical
baseless claims get published and they
become part of the uh
of the
academic canon
so the fact is that there is no basis on
which we can claim that the indus valley
people use so and so word or any other
word
for elephant or for any other thing
we don't know what language they spoke
we don't know what words they use we
have not been able to decipher the
script so this there itself this fails
the test of logic
right
and again on the basis of this
nonsensical claim
this individual has merely suggested the
possibility
that
this region spoke the ancient spoke some
ancestral dravidian language this is
absolute nonsense it doesn't stand up to
even the basic
cursory examination from the point of
view of logic or from the point of view
of facts right and secondly my question
is what are the dravidian languages
the dravidian language family was
invented by the christian missionary
bishop
caldwell bishop robert caldwell on the
basis of his
uh
half-hearted examination of just one
southern indian language
but because it is this great white
british christian person who has
given us this gift of this language
family our academicians have been
blindly following it like slaves for the
past century and it still continues so
we still continue to recognize this
artificial language family the so-called
dravidian language family even though
there is no evidence of the word dravida
in ancient indian literature whether it
is the tamil sangam literature or
sanskrit literature or any other
literature this is an artificial fake
language family that has been created by
this
non-expert whose real aim was to
christianize india and yet our
academicians our academics and our
students they blindly follow this
nonsense
so this is the problem that we face in
in even the most basic research
into ancient indian history
so
this claim
that the indus valley region saraswati
region people spoke in ancient language
it is patent nonsense it is absolute
nonsense it is garbage it belongs in the
trash bin and that is all i have to say
about this my friends
okay let's go on to question number two
abhishek says can you elaborate upon
the haplogroup fm89
okay so let us first understand what a
haplogroup is
a haplogroup is genetic lingo
for an ancestral lineage a blood lineage
a genetic lineage
so it means so a haplogroup is a group
of individuals who are alive today
and who are all descended from a single
individual who lived in the past
and who all carry a specific genetic
mutation from that one single individual
so it is a group of individuals it's an
extended family that is alive today who
all descend from a single individual who
lived long ago
and who who all carry a specific
mutation from that individual so it's a
lineage it's genetic lineage it's a
blood line in something that we would
call it a van
right so there are two kinds of
haplogroups
patrilineal haplogroups and matrilineal
haplogroups patrilineal haplogroups are
based on the
mutations carried in the y chromosome
that is passed on from fathers to sons
only males carry the y chromosome so
patrilineal haplogroups
are male lineages these are father to
sun descents over centuries or even
millennia and you have matrilineal
groups mitochondrial dna haplogroups so
the mitochondrial dna is found in males
as well as females but it is only passed
on from females to females from mothers
to daughters
so i carry mitochondrial dna all males
carry that mitochondrial dna but males
do not pass it on to their sons it is
only mothers who pass it onto their
offspring
so it is a female lineage that is a
mitochondrial dna lineage the
matrilineal haplogroups so this
haplogroup fm89
it is an ancient patrilineal haplogroup
all right it's a father to sun descent
it is a specific mutation that arose
about 60 to 62 000 years ago it it is
believed to be between 55 and 65 000
years old it means that today there is a
group of males
who carry this mutation
and the originator of this mutation was
one single male
who lived between 55 and 65 000 years
ago so it is a very ancient
patrilineal lineage haplogroup fm89 now
let me show you the
uh
geographic
origin of this lineage let me share
that specific image
all right here we are
this is the geographical origin of
haplogroup
m
uh yeah this is the haplogroup fm89
so this haplogroup this
patrilineal lineage originated in the
indian subcontinent between 55 and 65
000 years ago
and this lineage
haplogroup fm89
is the ancestral lineage of more than 90
percent of the world's non-african males
so what this tells us is that there was
an there was a way a migration out of
africa
that gave rise to
all of humanity that exists today
right
and it says that this out of africa
migration of ancient homo sapiens
it came out of africa
and it settled the
initial point of settlement after the
migration
was the indian subcontinent about 65 000
years before today
so india is the
original out of africa founders zone it
is where humanity had its first
foundation zone it is where humanity
first settled down after moving out of
africa and from india
humanity spread all over the world
across eurasia eventually even into uh
north and south america and other places
and there were some back migrations back
into africa as well which is well
attested from genetic evidence
so
the original lineage
the original ancestor of more than 90
percent of the entire world's
non-african males is a single male who
lived in india between 55 and 65 000
years before today
so
that is what this uh genetic evidence
tells us the genetic evidence of
haplogroup
fm89
so all of this
all of this that you are taught about
india being invaded from elsewhere in
india getting india getting culture and
genetics from elsewhere i think this
image itself demolishes all of those
fake stories india is the ancestral
homeland of all non-african humans and
it is not just the male haplogroups
indian origin matrilineal haplogroups
are
the ancestors of more than 95 percent of
the world's non-european females
all right so this is genetic evidence it
is irrefutable genetic evidence
india is the origin of all non-african
humans more than 90-95 of all
non-african humans and this origin is
about 60
50 between 65 55 and 65 000 years before
today
so all the europeans all the americans
all the chinese
everybody
all non-africans are descended from
ancient indians this is the original you
could say aryan invasion or aryan
migration it is from india that everyone
spread outwards
that is
in brief about haplogroup
fm89
yatandra says asks did
mount baton and his family really hope
and try their best for the good of india
as mentioned in texts and shown in
movies
yeah
if you watch that movie what's it called
gandhi
the film that came out in 81 was it 1981
in which mohandas gandhi is portrayed by
ben kingsley in that movie they have
depicted lord mountbatten as a very
benevolent kind-hearted
person who tried his best to
achieve something good for india and who
tried to prevent partition and who was a
great friend of mr mohandas
gandhi
and mr nehru who are all great indian
patriots and freedom fighters etc so
that is the
story that we are told whether it's in
the movies whether it is in our text
books whether it is our teachers our
professors our academicians our media
our politicians
everybody
more or less portrays this bunch of
individuals as kind-hearted generous
people who wanted the best for india now
the fact is that mr mount baton was
a british man he he was british he was
an agent of the british empire
and his
task was to
smoothly partition india with the help
of uh
that other lawyer who came to india
what was his name i forget his name the
guy who actually drew the map
uh who drew the
boundary the artificial
boundary between india and pakistan so
this guy mountbatten his job was to
to
ensure a smooth transition of power
from the british
to the indians who were appointed by the
british to take over
power it was see independence the
independence of india was a transfer of
power from one set of crooks to another
set of crooks that's all it was it was
not a democratic process india did not
win freedom india was given freedom
so to say on the terms that the british
decided
so we could not form our own kind of
governance system because we did not
have our own constitution the first
prime minister of india was not even
elected he was selected that was nero
and all of this was uh overseen by mr
mountbatten and the purpose of this
entire process was to ensure that
britain
continued
to have a great deal of say in the
internal matters of india and pakistan
and it was designed to ensure that
britain's geopolitical interests in the
region especially in the
western regions of india and the gulf
region where they had these interests in
oil extraction and all that so it wasn't
designed to ensure that these british
geopolitical interests were safeguarded
and the best way to do it was to
partition india have a pro
for pro britain pakistan and a mildly
or moderately pro-britain india in the
hands of somebody who is an anglophile a
mentally colonized individual like mr
nehru and the and the various other
leaders of the congress party who are
all anglophiles who were all british
educated who were all english-speaking
and who owed everything in their life to
the benevolence and generosity of the
british empire
so that is the task that mount verton
was given
and
he also had to ensure that nehru
remained very much on the british side
and to do that he was even willing to
allow his wife to have an affair with mr
nero as is very well documented the
whole world knows it today
of course it is also known that mr
mountbatten was a homosexual and he was
well he had an interest in underage boys
which is a crime in any decent civilized
society but that's what the british did
that's what was their culture it is
still possibly part of the culture in
well certain
western countries
so
mr mountbatten went to the extent of
letting his wife carry on a
long-standing affair with mr jawaharlal
nehru the entire world knew it the whole
of india was it and this was all
designed to ensure that mr nehru was
forever indebted to the british and he
would continue to pursue pro-british and
pro-west policies in india and they knew
that mr nero was
not
a very capable
gentleman or individual he was not
capable of
bringing india back to on its feet and
that's what we see anyway right he
his regime his tenure as the prime
minister of india was the greatest
disaster that we fell in india in the
20th century and its effects are still
with us today
so mr mountbatten and his family were
all british agents they were imperial
agents they were agents of colonialism
and imperialism they did not care about
india they cared about transitioning
about having a smooth transition from
one set of crooks to another set of
crooks with the overall objective of
pursuing and furthering the british
national interest and the british
geopolitical ambitions and interests in
the region that is all it was
jen panda says as a chinese person the
chinese century of humiliation is one of
the few things about chinese history
that can bring me to tears even to this
day this is the biggest pain point of
chinese history for most chinese people
today today yes so i have spoken about
this in a previous episode the opium
opium wars and how the western colonial
powers tried to oppress and break china
and they did humiliate china they did
impose all these unequal trade treaties
they
um
they um
pushed in a great enormous amounts of
opium into the country and extracted
genuine wealth out of the country silver
and gold
and they essentially impoverished china
for a century
uh this only happened for a century so
they were not able to totally infiltrate
the chinese empire the chinese mainland
and they were not able to impose the
english language in the chinese the way
they have done to india
so this is a very uh tragic
century in in
chinese history that also includes the
uh
imperial invasion from japan etc
so everything prior to the mr mao's
takeover of china is
kind of part of this entire scheme this
entire century of humiliation so this is
what is taught in every chinese textbook
every chinese student learns this it is
drilled into their heads that because
china was weak because china was not
capable of defending itself this is what
happened to china and the lesson is that
they should never ever ever ever happen
again to china and the lesson is that
china needs to strengthen itself
economically militarily and in all other
ways
in order to ensure that this sort of
humiliation is never brought upon china
again
so this is a very interesting
counterpoint to the neighboring
civilization the older civilization
which is india india has suffered a
millennium of humiliation and the
contrast is that india's textbooks
glorify the humiliators those who
humiliated in oppressed india india has
suffered the worst genocide in human
history more than 500 million indians
died over a millennium of foreign
occupation
first the turkic occupation which itself
may have killed about 500 million
indians
and then the
western occupation starting from various
countries but it ended up as the british
raj the british alone killed i would say
more than 200 million indians
this is the worst genocide in human
history but our textbooks don't speak
about it they don't they do not refer to
this period as the millennium of
humiliation humiliation they actually
glorify and extol the virtues of our
turkic and european and christian
occupiers
and our entire uh
bureaucratic system the judiciary system
the uh political system the
parliamentary system the western style
fake democracy and the academic system
everything is still completely 100
colonized it is still we are still aping
the inferior model of the west
so this is the contrast between india
and china the chinese won their
independence through violence there was
this protracted civil war
and it was a war of independence
essentially the communists
emerged victorious
and they set about extinguishing all
traces of foreign occupation and
everything that could be ascribed
to
foreign influences they
it did cause a great deal of destruction
in china one cannot deny that mao's rule
was horrific
maybe 80 90 100 million chinese died
because of his mismanagement but at the
end of the day the chinese have been
able to emerge out of it and it is a
proud nation it is a chinese nation they
don't learn anything in english they
don't they reject the english language
their entire education is in english so
this is all a product of the education
the historical education they are given
they are reminded every day that they
have undergone this humiliation and it
should never happen again
indians are anesthetized against this
indians are told that the past 1000
years were the best thing that could
happen to india so this is the origin of
india's slave-mindedness people in india
unfortunately it is true they are
slave-minded they are all mentally
colonized they they hate indian culture
they think everything bad that is in
india is because of indian culture
because of our backwardness inferiority
and all that caste is all indian and we
were all castiest and we were oppressive
and we were brahminical and we were
patriarchy patriarchal and misogynistic
all of this is a consequence of the past
1000 years but we are taught to believe
that this is all because of our
backwardness and because of the
inferiority of our culture and the
result is very apparent and visible
today india is becoming more and more
divided india is becoming more and more
un-indian and hindu phobic etc so this
is the contrast between india and china
the chinese recognize the century of
humiliation and they have
decided it will never happen again and
india embraces the past millennium of
humiliation and india hates everything
about itself
so this is what we need to wake up from
so please
wake up my friends
sahih rule hawk says i am an indian
muslim and i am growing an interest in
knowing
ancient indian history culture and
society
how are the ramayana and mahabharata
related to each other if not then what
are the differences i am asking about
context and time period and social
system etc at the time so it's an
enormous question you asked it's like
see
firstly we don't quite know when the
mahabharata happened and when the
ramayana happened uh there are a lot of
claims that researchers have brought out
that the richest researchers have put
forth based on various uh evidences that
we have especially our q astronomical
evidence but yet that the there are lots
of competing claims so we don't know for
sure yet when the mahabharat happened
and when the ramayana happened what we
know is that
the mahabharata is a more recent event
and the ramayana is a much older event
these were two very distinct phases in
indian history and both are several
thousand years old
so that's what we know about these two
very important chapters of indian
history now how was the society it was
indian society it was a pre-invasion
society there were no traces of either
turkic culture or arabic culture or
western christian culture etc etc it was
purely indian that's what we know the
ramayana is an older event it is the the
story of lord rama who was sent into
exile by his father
on the insistence of his stepmother who
was his father's second third whatever
wife
and it is the adventures that befall
upon
him his brother and his wife during the
exile his wife is kidnapped
devi sita is kidnapped by the
tyrannical
barbarian ravan who lives in the island
of lanka
and then the entire thing is to
recapture to to
to free
devi sita from the clutches of this
barbarian this of these of this demon
who is portrayed as a demon
so that is what it is so in the the the
geopolitical milieu of the region is is
such that uh
lord rama is the
king or the prince of ayodhya in
northern india which is the region of
delhi today
and
and he goes all the way to the south of
so the southern regions of india crosses
the ocean and reaches lanka so it is an
advanced adventure that spans the entire
indian subcontinent more or less
at least from the from northern regions
to the southern regions in the
mahabharata it is uh the battle it is it
is a war for the throne of hastinapur
which is again in northern india in the
region of delhi nearby
and it is uh a fratricidal war it is a
war between within a single family
between two sets of cousins
and a lot large number of other kingdoms
are also involved so the
war is not for the whole of india it is
merely for the throne of hastinapur and
many other kingdoms are involved from
from gandhara all the way to the
northern parts of india now afghanistan
and many other
kingdoms were also involved
so it looks like during the mahabharata
era india was more densely populated you
have many more competing kingdoms and
all that compared to the ramayana era
we don't know exactly what form of
indian languages was spoken most likely
some form of sanskrit whether it was
most likely post-vedic forms of sanskrit
and most likely pre-paninion forms of
sanskrit but the panini form of sanskrit
arose
perhaps around 500 bce
roughly that is that is the rough time
period when
the great
great panini the great uh
linguist and grammarian panini lived and
his sanskrit the sanskrit that he
codified is the classical sanskrit and
everything that came before that is
either vedic or post
sanskrit i am sure there was pre-vedic
sanskrit as well
so that is in brief about the
ramayana mahabharata era these are
definitely historical events western
scholars and indian mentally colonized
scholars and indian marxist historians
will
definitely say that these are myths but
these are simply their opinions there is
a great deal of evidence that attests to
both these periods of indian history and
to both these wars
dwarka and the rama sethu that totally
proves that these events happen the only
thing is we need to determine when these
events happened so that is in brief in
very brief i cannot i mean you could
have a week-long lecture session to talk
about the
kind of society
and the social system and
political system etc and military
tactics you had in those eras but i'm
just giving you a five-minute answer
maybe that can set you off in the
direction of studying this further
sanatori says you've opinionated on the
context of sanskrit to be the official
language of india want the muslim
majority won't the muslim
population particularly express their
disapproval and if it becomes an
official language won't we have a
shortage of vocabulary especially when
it comes to subjects like chemistry
biology sciences etc and do we even have
enough sanskrit literature so yes i am
of the opinion that sanskrit should be
india's official
civilizational language which it is a
status this language have has had for
thousands of years it is
this alienation of our ancestral
civilization language from us that is
deracinating us and it is contributing
to india's decline as a culture as a
nation as a civilization we are uh
losing our roots we are losing our
heritage
we are losing touch with our own culture
and our heritage so and sanskrit is the
oldest known language and it is the
language
that is the richest and most
scientifically oriented so the question
is want the muslim people
express their disciple i don't see why
the muslim people people should express
any disapproval towards sanskrit it is
their ancestral language as well the
indian muslims are our brothers and
sisters they are the descendants of
indians all their ancestors were indians
whether it is india pakistan afghanistan
bangladesh or wherever else their
ancestors are the same as us the dna is
the same as us so i don't see why they
should they would not want to honor the
language of their forefathers and four
mothers
i don't see any reason why that would be
true if certain
political outfits within that community
expressed their disapproval then they
would be in a small minority
india is a democracy
and in democracy the will of the people
is is what matters
there will always be some opposition
here and there i mean your name is
anatomy you're from manipur right in
manipur i know there's a there's
opposition towards sanskrit from some
some people
and towards hindi as well and there is a
there is this new wave of youngsters who
coming in and who are demanding that
english should be the official language
i mean do you even know the history of
manipur do you know what happened in
1891 what the british did to the people
of manipur they hanged your crown prince
in public in front of 8 000 manipuris in
the city of imphal
yes and the great general thangal
do you know how they destroyed manipuri
society and yet today's youngsters in
manipur
want english they they love english this
is because of de-racination because
you're not taught what happened because
that
because you don't have any emotional
connection to what happened just a
century ago to the humiliation
and and the atrocities that were
perpetrated upon the people upon the
people of manipur
so this is the kind of thing that's
happening in india we are destinated we
have lost touch with our past and that's
why we worship all these false gods
and the false ideals and
these inferior languages and inferior
foreign cultures
the point is sanskrit has to be brought
back as the official language of india
it is the only language that is suitable
and would be acceptable to all
right-minded people i'm not saying
left-minded to right-minded i mean all
intelligent people who know their true
history
and whether it is in southern india
northern india east west wherever it is
it is the only language that can serve
as the cultural and civilizational
language of india some people will
always express disapproval and lots of
there are lots of political outfits and
parties that oh everything
they who owe their legitimacy to
creating divisions in society for
example in the southern states of india
you have all these tamil supremacist and
tamil chauvinist parties
that oppose everything that is non-tamil
especially everything that is aryan so
to say and
their legitimacy
comes from the fact that they have
created these divisions in society
and they've created this false
sense of alienation in society that uh
the tamils have been oppressed for two
thousand or five thousand years by the
aryans and that's why we need to have a
tamil identity reject everything that's
non-aryan these are all fake
categories that have been created by the
british
so
once india is a little bit more educated
and more in touch with its actual true
history this sort of disapproval or
opposition will come down and of course
you need a strong leader who can
actually do this there will always be
opposition no matter where you are in
the world
and that's why you need strong
leadership
in the absence of a strong leader india
will remain disunited and fragmented
only when you have a leader of the
caliber
of the greats of the past
will india unite again and that is
that can happen
almost overnight you know once you have
a strong leader in in place
so okay the other question is once if it
becomes an official language will we not
have a shortage of vocabulary especially
when it comes to subjects like chemistry
biology etc you know sanskrit is the
richest language in the world it has
more than
more than 90 synonyms for the word love
it has more than 30 synonyms for the
word snow and it has the richest
scientific vocabulary in the world
the uh
the russian chemist mendeleev who is the
father of chemistry the father of the
periodic table he assigned sanskrit
prefixes to the elements in the periodic
table so he recognized the superiority
of sanskrit or latin or any other
european language in terms of uh
in the in the nomenclature
of sci of chemical elements and other
scientific words
i would say that sanskrit is actually
better suited than latin
in uh
the nomenclature of taxonomy of animals
and species
and all that and other things as well
i would say that once sanskrit is uh
officially it becomes the language of
education especially in science a new
vocabulary will automatically evolve
from the usage of sandi etc that covers
all of these subjects including the most
advanced cutting-edge scientifics of
this quantum mechanics spring theory
what not it's it's trivial to uh
to create a nomenclature for all of
these uh
all of these subjects in sanskrit and
the last question is do we even have
enough sanskrit literature
you know if you take
the literature in sanskrit
or the ancient literature the vedas the
puranas the upanishads the various
philosophical treatises whether it is in
whichever philosophical school of
thought whether it is uh border jaina
sankhya mimansa yoga yoga vedanta
whatever if you take all of this
together
the amount of literary texts that we
have the corpus of literary texts
is more than all of the ancient
literature in in all the western
languages put together in just one one
language sanskrit
it is one lifetime is not enough to read
even two percent or one percent of this
entire corpus of sanskrit literature
that is how much related literature we
still have despite all of our ancient
universes being burned down in the
libraries with them
so uh that is not even an issue we have
so much sanskrit literature it
it can sustain
generations upon generations of scholars
so i hope i have answered these
questions
sagar says that if everyone in ancient
india spoke sanskrit and it was perfect
why did people come up with different
languages like telugu canada etc it's a
valid question good question many people
would be wondering
look
sanskrit is the ancient
cultural and civilizational language of
india
it doesn't mean it was the only language
in india
india is a
subcontinent-sized geographical region
we know how diverse india is
there are so many
sub-cultures and regions in india if you
go from one village to another village
in a single state you will see a
different culture a different dialect
being spoken there a different cuisine
different way of dressing themselves etc
a different ways of
whatever rituals they perform etc so you
know india is an enormously diverse
place and there is an enormous amount of
linguistic diversity in india even
during the vedic age when vedic sanskrit
was prevalent there would be hundreds of
other languages and dialects
that were around it is not a linear
descent from one language to another
in a small region
let's say
a small european country you would have
that sort of thing for example in italy
you had ancient latin then you had
classical latin and then it became
italian
and even in a small place like italy you
had other languages too
sardinian language the sardinian
language and various other languages
those were wiped out eventually by the
predominance of latin because this was a
hegemonic society
in a vast society like india you had
hundreds of languages flourishing all
the time in parallel with each other it
was never a linear descent once you had
this language then it's a descendant
language was this and then that it's
never been like that it's been a vast
network
of different languages
right
so you had
many languages evolving in parallel
hundreds of languages but the one
civilizational language was always
sanskrit so people would typically learn
in the education system their mother
tongue and they would also learn
sanskrit
and sanskrit would be the medium of
education in scientific subjects
mathematics logic and various other
subjects like uh
history geography and whatnot
so it has always been a two language
system your mother tongue and this
civilizational language always the
cholas
take the cholas for instance they spread
all across southeast asia they conquered
the entirety of southeast asia it's one
of the greatest maritime
empires of all history
and which language did they propagate
all across these regions it was sanskrit
not tamil and some people will say that
there is tamil being spoken in singapore
and malaysia etc that is because of
tamil influx during the british
occupation of this region it is not
because of the cholas the cholas spread
sanskrit everywhere tell me something do
the people of indonesia have tamil names
or sanskrit names
do the people
the the the
the kingdoms in cambodia malaysia
uh
vietnam
etc in the philippines in all these
regions and in indonesia also did these
kingdoms have tamil names or sanskrit
names sanskrit so sanskrit has always
been the high language of culture and
civilization and people have always
spoken also their mother tongue whatever
it is
but everyone across india not south east
west always recognized sanskrit as the
civilizational language
that's why you have hundreds of
languages and dialects in india but you
also had sanskrit always so i hope
that explains
why it is so
rishi says you asked us to learn
sanskrit but where to start how to start
please guide about this okay here we go
read this book
this book is called
sanskrit swayam shikshak
it is the world's best book for learning
sanskrit note it down sanskrit swayam
shikshak you start this book within 30
minutes you will be speaking sanskrit
you will be forming your first words and
sentences in sanskrit if you study this
for three months you will be good at
conversational sanskrit
you have to study 30 minutes a day each
lesson is 30 minutes long you have to
study for three months if you study for
three months you will be well on your
way to becoming a master in sanskrit
this book is in hindi it is not in
english it is not available in english
so the only requirement is that you
should know hindi you should have some
familiarity with hindi if you can do it
i mean if i could learn it so can you
so this is the best book go buy it it's
very cheap it's available online
maybe next month in the book giveaway i
will give out a few copies of this book
so note it down sanskrit swayam shiksha
who is the author
sripad damodar sathav laker
that is the author
check it out buy the book and start
learning it is a brilliant book the best
book in the world for learning sanskrit
karan rana says do
were dogs like animals where animals
like dogs seen as true companions in our
ancient times
uh basically how they were treated
compared to today's time especially in
mahabharata and ramayan era
see we know that the indian species of
dog the indian breed of dog is the
ancestor of all dogs is the oldest breed
of dog in the world
and it's it's been india for
tens of thousands of years it is a
naturally evolved breed of dog for
example in the west and other places you
have all these fancy dog breeds
alsatians and german shepherds and
dalmatians and chihuahuas and poodles
and pomeranians and whatnot
great danes
saint bernards and
all these dogs these are all
artificially bred
species of dogs
not species breeds of dogs so they have
been bred selectively to enhance certain
traits
and these dogs everywhere in the world
these artificially bred
breeds of dog they are prone to
various illnesses
etc they don't live very healthy lives
and all the indian breed of dog this
indian street dog the yellow brown dog
you know the pariah dog they call it
this is the world's oldest breed of dog
it's naturally evolved it is naturally
resistant to all kinds of illnesses
and other problems it is one of the most
intelligent breeds of dog it is the most
social and friendly breed of dog and
it's always been around as
long as indian civilization has existed
so i don't know about the ramayana time
but in the mahabharat there is this very
famous
episode right after the war is over the
pandavas are instructed to
uh
renounce their kingdom because their
duty is done and the next generation is
to take over
and they essentially go to the himalayas
to spend out their lives there and
ascend to the summit of mount meru which
is where swargalok is
so their work on the planet earth is
done it is time for them to move on so
beam
arjun and the the five brothers and
draupadi the wife they all move on to
the himalayas they start crossing the
himalayas
and one after the other these brothers
and dropper they also they one after the
others start dying because of the harsh
conditions of the himalayas at the end
yudhisthira is left with a companion who
is a dog so this dog started with these
five with these six at the beginning of
the journey at the end only yudhisthira
is left with the dog and yudhisthira
starts climbing the
great mountain mount meru or mount
kailash
with the dog the dog dog accompanies him
everywhere
and when he's climbing the mountain
maybe he's like one third of the way up
uh lord indra himself comes on his
chariot on his flying chariot and he
tells you that your work is done you
don't need to climb all the way up you
just need to hop into my chariot i'll
take you to swargaloka so yudhisthira
says that okay i will do it let me let
my dog get in first so lord indra says
no this is for you it's not for the dog
so yudhisthira
refuses to climb on the chariot unless
the dog is also allowed he says that
this dog has been faithful to me
throughout my journey i cannot betray
this dog he is my friend he is my
companion and then the dog transforms
into a human form in the in into the
form of the great deity dharma
and he says that you are the true
dharmaraj because you have always
followed dharma
so that kind of illustrates the
relationship that we indians and our
ancestors for thousands of years have
had with dogs we have always cherished
the dog as our best friend it has been
our companion for thousands of years and
this is brought out in the form of this
little anecdote from the
mahabharata era
so yeah we have always see india has
always been kind to animals compared to
any other culture
for example our chinese neighbors they
are a more recent culture and
civilization
they do not
uh see
compassion as one of the uh
key components of their culture
and you can see that in the the way they
treat animals which well i would not
even want to talk about right the
treatment of animals is rather
horrific
in contrast in india of course people
did eat meat in the
forever essentially i mean if you look
at the ancient uh
stone age iron age
uh
archaeological artifacts you you do find
fishing hooks and harpoons and all that
which was used in fishing and hunting
you do find these you find depictions in
the bimbakes etc or people hunting
animals so it has always been part of
indian culture but cruelty has never
been part of indian culture
indian culture has always been
compassionate indian culture has always
treated animals with compassion and
dignity and love even when animals were
hunted there was no unnecessary cruelty
right
and
dogs especially were
our great companions for essentially
forever
and that we can see in the story of
yudhisthira and his friend the dog who
so
in indian society and culture and
civilization dogs do go to heaven all
right
okay
pink line caps
why didn't the mighty cholas launch an
attack on northern india maybe they
could have in saved india from the
tyrant mahmoud ghazni or other
invaders that's an interesting question
so the cholas
the the pinnacle of the cholas was
rajyandra chola and raj raj wasn't it
the two great kings who lived in the
at the end of the 10th century and the
beginning of the 11th century and it is
uh
i think it was who was it
i think it was rajratullah who expanded
the kingdom to its greatest extent the
empire to its greatest greatest extent
all across southeast asia
and this these two kings the father and
the son
they
were in power one after the other during
roughly the period of these invasions
when these invasions from mahmoud of
ghazni etc happened in india
so the question is why didn't they uh
intervene and expel this
tyrant this invader art of india and
back into his lair in the mountains of
ghazni in northern india in afghanistan
the thing is these guys see in those
days
we did not have instant communication
the way we have today
if an invasion is happening and the
local solanki king calls up rajiraj
chola and says hey this is happening we
need your support so in that case this
guy may have been able to come all the
way to northern india in maybe two three
weeks
and he could have provided
assistance to the kings in northern
india but in those days india i mean
we we are accustomed to seeing india on
the map as this big
it's enormous it's actually an enormous
subcontinent sized geographical region
and traversing distances of thousands of
kilometers takes months actually
especially when you have something as
large as an army which is a hundred
thousand plus strong with all the
equipment and all the logistics it
entails
so even if raja raja chola had come to
know
about what's happening in northern india
it would have taken him a great deal of
time to come all the way to north india
secondly most likely he did not come to
know until many months later
right and his entire focus his entire
energies were dedicated in southeast
asia where he was where he had this
enormous empire there's a great deal
there's a lot of
complications
and there's a lot of things that you
need to attend to when you are learning
and running an enormous empire that
large and you don't have instant
communications so he was his entire
life was preoccupied in
building and consolidating and
administering this
enormous empire in
india in southern india and southeast
asia all the way up to the philippines
so firstly he would have not come to
know about what's happening and secondly
even if
he had come to know maybe he was not in
a position to come and divert his entire
focus energies and army into northern
india maybe that could have led to the
downfall of his empire in south east
asia
because if you divert all of your
resources your energies your soldiers
etc to northern to another part of the
world then the local kings etc will
declare themselves independent it is the
nature of power power abhors a vacuum
so that vacuum was filled by the chola
empire had they redirected their
energies and manpower and supplies to
another place there would have been a
power vacuum in south asia in southeast
asia and that would have been
instantaneously filled by the local
kingdoms they would have all declared
themselves independent and the chola
empire would have crumbled overnight
and the third reason is that perhaps
most likely even if he wanted to do all
this his empire was a maritime empire
his empire's strengths military strength
was in the maritime domain it was a
thalassocratic empire a maritime empire
so they knew how to fight naval wars and
naval battles they were suited for that
maybe they don't they did not have the
kind of infantry and
strategic and tactical uh experience
needed to to fight a long protracted
military campaign on land
especially the kind of uh
geography you have in northern india so
these are some of the reasons why
it was not possible for the cholas
to
intervene in northern india to go all
the way to north india and repel the
invaders who came from beyond
okay this is a whole lot of questions
all related to cast
kulip says like you mentioned a few
times in previous videos hinduism
doesn't need any reform but it needs to
rejuvenate how would you explain the
castism that was and still is so much
deep-rooted even today
in the so-called modern and progressive
india
om says when did cast base oppression
start in bharat and what are the reasons
it continued until now
the next question is did the british
remove the caste system and educate
indians by building schools
and hitkeshwagara says why are the
surnames of rajputs and dalits the same
in gujarat
a bunch of questions all related to
caste
okay so let's begin let me share some
literature with with you all let me hide
this and share my screen
okay just give me a minute
i need to make a few recommendations
reading recommendations and study
recommendations
where are we
this is a book recommendation
so i have
stated in the past that the caste system
is a western invention many of you have
been skeptical and you have said that
this is all something i pulled out of my
hat it's not
uh so this is one book recommendation
the western foundations of the caste
system by martin farrell
etc etc etc a good book i would
recommend this and if you want a review
of this book
an overview of this book then i would
suggest
this
it is a book review by somia day on
india facts look it up on google find
this article
read it it it demonstrates how the west
how the british essentially uh imposed
this artificial construct called the
caste system on india here is one more
book recommendation
it is casts of mind colonialism and the
making
of modern india it's by nicholas dirk
this is also an excellent book
so this also tells you how the british
created this fake
artificial caste system
and i would recommend one more article
by a guest who has been on this podcast
before dr subhash
this is called the idea of india in
which he also goes into
uh how the west especially the british
created all these artificial divisions
in indian society
so these are some recommendations you
can pause the video later when you're
watching
and check out these uh
articles and
books
online
if you are serious about understanding
this i would recommend that you should
actually read these articles and even
study the books in detail
otherwise
well i can't force you to do that but if
you're serious in understanding
all this then you should actually spend
the time invest the time in studying
this to understand
how this country has been
misled
okay so let me come back to this so my
point is this is a british creation we
believe because of our education system
etc and because of our brainwashed
uh previous generations the past two
three generations who are all thoroughly
brainwashed so we believe that the caste
system is an ancient indian evil it is
one of the uh forms of backwardness of
indian society our ancestors were evil
like somebody said once
so this is all nonsense
okay let me take up swagela's question
why are the surnames of rajputs and
dalits the same in gujarat because
they're the same people
they are the same people there is no
such thing as this fake cast there have
been divisions in society jaati and
verna verna is occupation jati is your
lineages like you have this haplogroups
that we spoke about some time ago
india is home to thousands of jatis
thousands of petroleum and metrolina
lineages
and you have varnas which are these
ancestral occupations
it is prevalent all over the world if
you look at british surnames
one of the most common surname is smith
what is smith it is a metal worker what
is blacksmith black blacksmith is a
common british surname a blacksmith is a
metal worker what is thatcher a thatcher
is somebody who touches roofs this is a
medieval occupation people still carry
that surname so these occupations have
been passed on from generation to
generation to generation it stays within
families this is prevalent all over the
world if you look at every single
british surname english-speaking people
surname you will find this ancestral
occupations these are
varnas
this is prevalent all over the world it
is not exclusive to india itself right
now what about the rajputs and the
dalits
so the rajputs are the
have traditionally been the chatria's
the the war warrior class the
aristocracy of the country
the kshatriyas have been the aristocrats
the brahmins have been the ones who
uh
preserved the country's knowledge the
civilization's knowledge for thousands
of years
so the entire society in india even
today we revere knowledge
we we
we respect people who are knowledgeable
right people who are learned people who
are scholarly we worship them many of
many of us actually worship such people
that is because of our inbuilt
reverence for knowledge it is it is
built into our dna
and naturally the people who were the
most learned
for thousands of years were the people
who passed it on from generation to
generation the the brahmins but it was
not exclusively
for within a certain certain families
you could become a scholar on your own
as we know very well from our ancient
universities every it was open to
everybody even a chinese person like
swan zhang was admitted
into nalanda university the highest seat
of learning in the known universe at the
time
so that is what made him a brahmin
because he was able to get admission
there now when it comes to rajputs and
dallas why are these names the same it
is because
when the
turkic occupations turkic invasions and
occupation of india happened in gujarat
and among other rajputs also
they gave three choices it was not two
choices it was three choices
convert
die or declare yourself a shudra
so many rajputs
chose to die
they would not convert they would not do
anything anything like that many rajputs
converted the entirety of the pakistani
army is muslim rajputs
muslim rajput
uh what's his name that other fellow the
previous chief of staff is rajput they
are all muslim rajputs and they are
proud of being muslim rajputs they are
proud of their rajput lineage so many
rajputs converted
and some rajputs refused to convert they
refused to die so they declared
themselves shudras that we are no longer
rajputs we will no longer fight
so that these are the three conditions
that the invaders imposed upon
the ones who could fight and resist them
that's why
and some actually survived some fought
some resisted and some survived so you
have hindu rajputs you have muslim
rajputs and you have the so-called
rajputs they are the same people
the same ancestry the same dna isn't
that interesting
okay
so this is the truth about the caste
system i i will definitely make a
detailed
video about this a separate stand-alone
video about this because this is a this
is a complex topic it needs to be
unpacked and analyzed properly
but i have given you some book
recommendations i have given you a
couple of articles to read do that if
you are serious about understanding this
and
i i hope you guys do it you know
okay next question
krishna says if afghanistan is called
the graveyard of empires then how did
maharaja ranjit singh manage to control
and rule afghanistan so maharaja ranjit
singh did not
control and rule the entirety of
afghanistan
he what he did was
he freed
many regions of india
northern and western india especially
punjab and kashmir
from the occupation that began with
ahmad shah abdullah so ahmad shabdali
was a pashtun
uh he was an invader he
it is with ahmad shah dali that the
afghans start considering themselves as
non-indians because ahmad shabdali
emperor persian king in his invasion of
india which turned into a horrific
bloodbath
so it is with ahmad shah abdali in the
17th 18th century thereabouts that
afghanistan
became
a separate
uh ethnocultural and political entity
so this guy ahmad shabdali he launched
seven or eight invasions of india he
took over kashmiri took over parts of
punjab and he perpetrated horrible
atrocities in these regions it is the
beginning of the kashmir problem it is
when a significant population
significant percentage of the kashmiri
population got converted
and that is where everything originates
right
so maharaja ranjit singh freed kashmir
he expelled the pashtuns the afghans out
of kashmir out of punjab and as a
punitive measure he conquered
uh
significant portions of afghanistan but
not the whole of afghanistan he did not
conquer kabul he did not conquer other
northern parts of afghanistan but he
conquered the southern regions of
afghanistan
the regions that are now south of the
duran line and which lie in pakistan so
all of that was maharaja ranjit singh's
empire
right so how did he manage to expel the
afghans from their occupation of kashmir
in pakistan of punjab etc it's because
he
instituted a number of wide-ranging
reforms
in his military
one of the major regions the reasons why
indians were losing to the europeans was
because of the
different tactics the europeans had and
the different weapons the more modern
weapons they brought with themselves so
maharaja ranjit singh employed european
mercenaries in his army he uh
he
he rose them to uh various
positions of reasonable prominence in
the army but he never appointed them as
overall generals or anything but he did
elevate them to
positions of eminence and prominence in
the army and their tactics were adopted
into the
army of maharaja ranjit singh
and new weapons were also were also
inducted into the army and it is and the
entire focus
of the military operations was on
winning
by any means whatever tactics are
necessary were to be employed and we
were to win and reclaim
uh our territories
so it is because of this
change in approach
and because of this more modern and more
practical more pragmatic approach that
maharaja ranjit singh was able to
expel the afghans out of indian
territories
and to actually capture and retain
the southern regions of afghanistan as
well
this is a long question it is by jijo
alex kakkatyu
he says that this may seem self-serving
but in any case hearing from you will
probably highlight the case about the
lack of understanding of the general
populace about my community the syrian
christians of kerala
i know you've said there is no
historical proof of saint thomas having
traveled to india
you have to understand also that there
is no not any there's no proof regarding
the existence of jesus christ
either
but you have to agree to the fact that
the existence of christians in kerala
long before the europeans embraced the
religion i would also like to point out
that my community has been persecuted by
the portuguese simply because we did not
adhere to their culture and traditions
the current cross oath is the best
example of that the schisms in the
church in kerala at this time is
testament to all the politics that
portuguese and later the british played
although in kerala our existence is
understood it is my community's
existence that the other people of my
beloved country fail to understand we
are after all by faith christian and by
culture hindu
your point of view will shed some light
and many can then not conveniently paint
everyone with the same brush i agree
with you uh
jijo alex
this is a complex topic see the syrian
or syriac christians of kerala are a
community that seems to date back about
1900 years so clearly before any foreign
occupation or invasion or occupation of
india definitely more than a thousand
years before the european
invasions and occupation of india
especially in southern india it was the
portuguese
so the this
so the the syria syrian christian
community in india believes
that they uh were converted by thomas
the apostle
saint thomas who came to india preached
christianity and uh
and converted a number of people in the
malabar region in the in the kerala
region to uh christianity that is syriac
or syrian christianity they they
practice their liturgical rights in an
ancient
syriac language
a dialect of the old aramaic language i
believe
and when the portuguese
occupied this part of india they tried
to force these
christians indian christians
into adopting portuguese
uh a portuguese version of christianity
in which latin was the predominant
language not the aramaic dialect
so they tried to impose this upon the
local christians upon the syrian
christians they tried to impose latin
and other forms of other portuguese
forms of worship
so at some point in time after about 50
years the syriac syrian christians
rebelled against the portuguese they
made this wow of affirmation which is
called the coolant cross oaths in which
they rejected the portuguese flavor of
christianity and reverted to their
older
rituals and uh aramaic
language etc so they reverted to their
older
uh version or or rights of christianity
so this was a
repudiation
of the european culture that had been
brought into this part of india
so definitely it is true that the syrian
christians are a much older community it
is believed to be about 1900 or so years
old
the belief is that it is saint thomas
who converted them to christianity so
listen the thing is this you are right
there is no evidence of saint thomas
there is no evidence of
the lord jesus himself
they have archaeologists have been
searching for evidence of jesus christ
for
decades or centuries and thus far there
is no hard evidence it doesn't mean he
may not have existed he may perhaps
have existed
uh thomas the apostle also most likely
existed the only question is did he ever
come to india i have no question i have
no issue with even if he actually did
come to india the
issue is the portrayal of indians in the
story they portray indians as as as
primitive barbarians who who killed
thomas the apostle because he was
converting indians there is no evidence
that this gentleman ever came to india
firstly and secondly there is no
evidence whatsoever that he was murdered
by indians but this is now the canonical
story to show india in a bad light to
show the people of india in a bad light
so that is what i have a problem with
that is what all
indians would have a problem with with
this fake depiction this false
fabricated depiction of indians as
murderous barbarians right
but apart from that yes you are right
you the syrian christians are of course
by culture and by dna hindu the the
funny thing is that uh
the curious thing is that syrian
christians some of them call each other
call themselves mapila
the word mapila is a honorific term
that is uh
which means descendant of foreigners i
believe
even the
muslims of kerala call themselves mapila
it means a descendant of foreigners
especially from the middle east
so even the syrian christians
consider themselves to be at least some
of them consider themselves to be
descendants of people from the middle
east
from the uh
region of judea and and the arabic
regions etc
so this is uh i i this is a bit curious
i mean so does it mean that the syrian
christians
are
originally the descendants of some some
people who migrated to india from that
region
and is it is that how the religion was
brought into india so the origins of
this community are a little bit obscure
um
the the official version is that saint
thomas came and converted them but it
looks like because they call each other
etc that they may actually be the
descendants of a small group of migrants
who came to this part of india for
whatever reason it's like the afghan
pashtuns the afghan pashtuns they say
that we are the descendants of one of
the lost tribes of israel but dnl
analysis shows that there is no this is
not the case they are an extension of
the overall indian population
but the claim they make
to to perhaps to justify their
conversion to
to the other religion
to islam is that we are the descendants
of middle easterners and all that
and the pakistanis similarly claim
descent from turks
so i am not really sure what is the
origin of this community of course you
are very much indian you are indian by
dna uh you practice a much older form of
christianity than these europeans who
try to impose a different form of
christianity on you so
my culture hindu
i am not sure how
culturally hindu christianity is
um
yeah it is true that many christians in
india
have hindu names
i think the majority of christians in
india have hindu names but they practice
christianity so by that sense you could
say that yes
indian christians are to some extent by
by culture
hindu but on the other hand there is
definitely a very strong movement
towards explicitly rejecting hindu
culture among indian christians
especially
in the past one or two generations as
christian convergence pick up speed
right now which we are witnessing
everywhere
so this is a very uh complicated topic
it is uh the syrian christians are
definitely
one of the oldest christian communities
in the world if you go by the official
version that it is 1900 years old i
would like to see some sort of dna
analysis
as to to see exactly what sort of dna
uh
components this community has
uh is there any middle eastern or syrian
trace
of dna
among these people or not so that's an
interesting topic but
uh so yeah that's that's what i would
have to say about this this is a matter
for debate it's a matter that it needs
more
historical research dna research and and
much more
the uh
story of
thomas the apostle traveling to india is
very much a myth
some people said there is a church up on
some hill and that proves that the saint
thomas was in india
how does the presence of a building on a
hill
prove anything
i mean it proves nothing just because
there is a church on some hill or
whatever doesn't prove anything it's
just a building on a hill it doesn't
prove that some individual was in india
1900 years ago
the only way to prove that he was in
india was if his remains are found in
india or there is
undeniable literary evidence from
multiple sources that attests to the
fact that he was in india but
there is
a
marked absence of such evidence
debraj biswas asks how did the parcels
come to india and help india
we know they came to india but what
about help i'm not sure they
ever
helped india
so uh so here's what what we know about
the parsees
the parsees are uh
zoroastrians they are
the descendants of a of a
of a small group of of a reasonably
small group of refugees who escaped from
persecution in iran in persia
and who were granted refuge
in
western india in gujarat
so around these 8th century or so
seventh or eighth century up to the
ninth and tenth centuries there was this
great persecution of zoroastrians in
persia persia had been uh invaded and
conquered by the arabs
and the country was very rapidly
islamized and then there was this pogrom
against the zoroastrians they were all
uh given the optional option to convert
or die essentially
so many there was a great deal of
resistance for some time but within 20
30 years after the invasion the majority
of the population of portugal was
converted to
islam
so
some people tried to escape this
religious persecution this brutal
religious religious persecution and they
came to india in the hope of surviving
and the
king the local king in in gujarat at the
time he magnanimously allowed these
parsees these persians to settle down
in his kingdom in his territory in
western india in southern gujarat
the first place where they came to was a
small village called sanjan they named
the place sanjan after the town they
escaped from which is zanjan in iran so
they were allowed magnanimously by the
indian king to settle down in southern
gujarat they were allowed to
settle down and to continue
practicing their religion and culture
there would be no interference in their
activities the only condition is was
that they would assimilate harmoniously
with the local
uh people so they were to adopt the
gujarati language and gujarati dress
if they were to settle down there and
they agreed to this so it was a very
magnanimous
gesture towards these towards the
persians who were
escaping with their lives they settled
down in gujarat they adopted the
gujarati language and gujarati dress and
customs but they continued to practice
their culture their religion
zoroastrianism and
they have been doing this for the past
thousand plus years and there have been
several waves of migration of persians
so they were called parsees because
parsi comes from persia parsa parshwa
and the religion also came to be known
as parsi even in the 19th century there
were some more waves of migrations of
zoroastrians
into india into western india they were
called iranis as
in contra distinction with the older
earlier parsees but they're the same
people same
religion same culture
now if you look at the dna
if you look at the dna of the parses it
is quite strange that their matrilineal
dna the mitochondrial dna is closest to
the gujaratis
so they they are closest to the
gujaratis than to either the
maharashtrians or punjabis or bengalis
or
sindhis or persians in terms of
matrilineal dna but in terms of
patrilineal dairy they are closest to
the portions so this tells us a very
very interesting thing that these
parsees they
did not marry among gujarati men but
they did ex they did take gujarati women
into their families as wives
and that's why they are a mix of
persians and gujaratis
from the matrilineal side they are
almost exclusively nowadays
gujarati but from the patrilineal side
from the y dna by dna perspective they
are still to a significant extent
closest to the persians
now these guys these people they came
into india sometime around the 8th
century
between the seventh and the tenth
centuries more than a thousand years ago
and they settled down in gujarat and for
more than eight centuries they were a
small agricultural community
they were given all the freedom and all
the rights that every other gujarati or
indian had
and they were a small agriculture
community agricultural community they
uh
expanded to small towns like now sari
uduada
and even they even settled in in sindh
some of them there is still a very small
population of of parsees in karachi i
wonder what the condition is but they
are still there
and so on
because at the time even karachi was a
gujarati speaking to a large extent a
gujarati speaking city
so it was all along the same coast and
that's where they settled down for about
800 years they were a small
quiet
sedentary
uh agricultural community
now the strange thing is this when the
british occupied india
and when they
took over
western india
they identified the parsees
as a community to uplift so the british
they practiced this policy of divide and
rule there
it is this is what they have practiced
worldwide
they take a community they take a
society and they create artificial
divisions in the society
they play sides they take one community
uplift it and oppress everybody else so
they chose to uplift the parties the
special they they singled out the
parsees for special treatment
and what they did was that they bestowed
favors upon the parsees they allowed the
parties to
to to become closer to them as their
servants and and chauffeurs
and uh bankers and all that
they gave them uh benefits like
they allowed them to practice certain
trades and occupations
ship building etc
banking
uh
and all that so all of a sudden within a
few decades this community which had
achieved absolutely nothing for 800 or
thousand years suddenly became
industrialists and suddenly became very
wealthy
and today it is believed by all indians
that the parsis are a special
magnificent uh extraordinary
extraordinary people
who have
enriched india with their greatness
the fact is that they were given special
treatment by the british at the expense
of everybody else in india
and it is because of the british
largesse
that the pa that the power sees have
become so rich
and all of the wealth the power seas
have accumulated is actually the wealth
that was stolen from indians and by the
british and it was given over to the
parties and let me let me share
something with you
uh
so the parseys essentially
owe everything
everything that they have
two
british munificence so let me give you
an example of
of this
so this is a gentleman called
kawas g jahangir ready money
look at his surname ready money
so this guy
was a parsi
community leader
philanthropist and industrialist of
bombay india okay he was born into a
wealthy family parsi family
who were all
benefiting from generations of british
largest and generosity
and he was called ready money which he
by the british because he was always
generous in giving money donating money
to the british causes
and he actually took that as a surname
ready money
so
this is a fountain that he uh built
with
with his money in regents park london it
cost lots i mean a huge amount of money
and he he owned many large housing
estates in london etc
and he did a lot of philanthropy in
britain
such as building these fountains and
various other things
this here is a sculpture of
kawasaki jhangi ready money in the
college of edinburgh for his services to
british society and the tragic thing is
that at the time when he was
when he was investing when he was
donating millions of pounds or millions
of rupees of this money
to the british this was the time when
india was undergoing
year after year of terrible famines
millions of people were dying every year
in india because of artificial famines
created by the british
and these millions of rupees that he
donated for british causes could have
saved millions of indian lives
and everybody in india knew what was
happening at the time and yet he chose
as a good servant is a good slave
to please his british masters
and
and throw this money to bestow his money
which came from british generosity on
the british
so this is the kind of
of uh
enrichment the policies
did in india
and this
here
is his nephew jahangir kawasji dhangir
ready money
he was another prominent member of this
family he was the nephew of the previous
guy i showed
and he has been created he was created a
baronet in the united kingdom a baronet
is a rank in the british aristocracy so
this these ranks are given for services
to the british empire and the service
was to
basically enrich
and empower the british empire so the
fact is that all of this money
that the policies enjoy today
is
entirely a consequence of the british
generosity towards them it is because of
the british policy of divide and rule
they uplifted the parses at the expense
of everybody else whom they impoverished
and starved to death
and all of the money that these guys
enjoyed was money that actually belonged
to the people of india
and today the policies are the richest
community in india
it is all old money and when we talk
about old money it is money that has
been given to them that is they have
earned because of british generosity at
the expense of the people of india now i
have nothing against the parsi people
it is not their fault they are rich
today
it is not their fault at all i don't i
have i hold no grudge against the passes
they are very nice people i even know
some parsis
no issue with them but understand the
history
understand how these
impressions are created
that the policies have enriched india
with their superior
uh
with with uh with their extraordinary
qualities
they are today people think of parties
as
extraordinary industrialists and
entrepreneurs and all that the fact is
that indians have had this
entrepreneurial gene
for millennia
it is
traders from kalinga
who went all across southeast asia
and who built kingdoms in these regions
and enriched southeast asia as a
consequence
all the hinduised kingdoms in vietnam
the funan kingdom etc was all a
consequence of the
traders from kalinga the industrialists
and entrepreneurs from kalinga who
who embarked upon these
initially very danger dangerous and
perilous voyages into the unknown
and went all across asia later it was
the cholas and various other peoples
from india who went all across southeast
asia it was indian
monks during kanishka and kanishka's
time etc who crossed the himalayas and
went all the way thousands of kilometers
into china and enriched china with
indian culture
and also carried out trade in all kinds
of commodities it is indians who carried
out trade with rome
who sent ships to rome
it is indians gujaratis and these uh
marwari and gujarati banyas
who have been trade carrying out trade
for thousands of years in the country it
is gujaratis who settled down in eastern
africa for centuries and carried out
trade there it is this entrepreneurial
dna
is part of india of every indian
the parties are nothing special they did
not come to india and enrich us with
their presence
they were in india for 800 or thousand
years doing absolutely nothing they were
perfectly ordinary until the british
chose to
elevate them
with all this special treatment so that
is the history of the power says in
india in brief nothing against them they
are very nice people they are very
likable people as well absolutely
nothing against them but this is the
true history
siddhant says i have a hypothesis that
partition had an unintended positive
outcome for india a major portion of
separatists extremists jihadists etc
went to pakistan
now we have fewer of these people
to deal with
so we could avoid a lot of bad
reputation associated with pakistan etc
could india avoid another civil war
between separatists and nationalists is
there anything good that came out of
pakistan for india
and what would have been the picture if
partition didn't happen see partition
happened because of the congress party
because of the leadership of mr mohandas
gandhi and mr jawal nehru and various
other congress leaders it was all a
british agenda the british used the
congress party and the muslim league as
the tools for carrying out partition it
had a geopolitical objective like i have
spoken about several times even in uh
just a few minutes ago
so that was the objective of partition
and that is why they did partition now
had somebody like subhash chandra bose
being successful
in his campaign to take back india to to
liberate india from the british
let's let's uh examine a hypothetical
scenario in which subhashin rabos
liberates india from the british and
sets up an independent indian government
independent of the british or the
japanese
now would a person like subhash chandra
bose
have ever allowed partition
yes mr gandhi would have been in india
he would have advocated partition mr
jinnah would have advocated partition mr
nehru would have advocated partition and
the various muslim league leaders etc
the khilafat people etc would have
advocated partition what would somebody
like subhash narabose
have done
i suspect he would have shot them all
that's the kind of person he was
and that is
what he would have done in the face of a
demand for partition
for when sebastian rabos fought for
india's freedom
hindus muslims sikhs jains buddhists etc
fought for him they bled for him and
they died for him they died for mother
india
if subhash and bose had been successful
there would have been no partition and
any pro-partition elements in the
country would have been dealt with in a
terrible manner
so bashing there was bose wanted
dictatorship in india for at least 20
years
in today's world that would have been
called fascism
i don't care what it's called that's
what he would have done had he been the
president of india had he been the
leader of india
he possibly could
have been a stalin-like figure in india
and he would have stamped out any
anti-national or separatist opposition
thoroughly
so what you're talking about is that
there is so much jihadism and terrorism
and extremism in pakistan
because of all these elements went to
pakistan well the fact is that had india
not been partisan had somebody like
swashboth been there he would have dealt
with it severely and today there would
be no such elements in the country he
would have ruled india for 20 30 years
with an iron hand
and that iron hand would have ensured
that no such thing would have happened
we see history from the perspective of
what's happened today
but history could have been very
different it's all about leadership
if you have the right leaders then such
elements and such sentiments simply
don't emerge
in the country
india has its own distinct culture a
very ancient culture that would
eventually have
been revived
under the rule of somebody like
sebastian rabos
and any separatism would have been
stamped out so i
disagree that partition was good for
india india needed a strong leader an
iron fisted leader at the time when a
country emerges from a thousand years of
chair of chaos it doesn't need
liberal democracy it needs iron rule for
20 30 years
that's what you see everywhere in the
world it happened in china now china is
becoming slowly more progressively
different from what it was under under
chairman mao
south korea had 20 years of dictatorship
after the korean war
the japanese had
70 plus years of american occupation
the soviets had their own thing so so
the fact is that
had india not been partitioned and had
india had a strong leader like mr bose
then none of these problems would ever
have existed and that is why i have
always been saying that partition was a
terrible thing for india we lost our
ancestral territories
the territories our ancestors lived in
for thousands thousands of years it is
because the british wanted it and
because people like mr gandhi and mr
nehru and the various other congress
leaders and mr jinnah they all ensured
that this happens if mr bose had been
there this would never have happened and
there would have been no jihadism
extremism separatism kilapathism or
whatever else in india
sharon says while still immensely
respecting all sacrifices made by
martyrs against foreign occupying forces
do you think it is time to stop
portraying independence day as if india
as a nation was born on the day negating
thousands of years of prior independence
history and achievements before that
possibly even renaming the day to
something like veer yota divas or puddar
janmadivas
see india as a nation as a
westphalian nation state
was
created in 1947 out of something much
bigger
before 1947 india was a civilization
state that was under foreign occupation
before
if you go back more than a thousand
years before today india was a vast
civilization state that had sometimes a
single political dispensation one single
empire and sometimes it had multiple
kingdoms etc but it was always one
civilizational entity
in 1947
the civilization was destroyed it was
killed
and a much inferior version of it was
created as a westphalian nation state
so 1947 what happened 15th august 1947
should be a day of mourning for india it
was the day of transfer of power from
one set of crooks to another set of
crooks before 1947 indians were fighting
against everything the british stood for
against their system of governance
against their laws
against their judiciary against their
police against everything
after 1947 the same system continued
that we were opposing but now we were
told it is our own system
and that is how we were colonized
and that is how colonization was
perpetuated and we are still colonized
today somebody who is 15 years old
thinks that this entire system
is our own system
that we ourselves made
while it is not it is the oppressive
british colonial system so 1947 was the
year indians all the wool was pulled
over the indians eyes and the same
system was continued but under the guise
of being your own system
so in india in 1947 india was truncated
india became something much lesser
india became something much inferior to
what it has always been
from a civilization state india became a
mere
nation state
so i don't think that this is something
we need to celebrate it is something we
need to mourn it should be called
transfer of power give us from one set
of crooks to another set of crooks we
gained nothing
we gained a new set of rulers a new set
of oppressors in 1947 and the same
system continues today of course i'm not
saying today's
rulers all of them are oppressive many
of them mean well but it's taking a lot
of time to change this we're not seeing
any real change in real time which is
disappointing
so that is what it was it was a transfer
of power india was not born in 1947
india we don't even know when india was
born definitely more than ten thousand
years ago even
probably much more much before that
so 1947 is actually
a tragic year
and it is the year that we
adopted
the british ways which we were supposed
to reject
samarjeet says aren't we following the
british legacies like the judiciary
system the administrative system etc we
are still using the british railways and
keeping the british architecture even
after they are the epitome of evil and
they are unjust
so does that make us good or bad look
good question good question uh i do keep
saying that we need to reject the
british constitution the western
constitution of india the british laws
that we still continue the british
system the entire colonial system etc
now when it comes to british railways
and british architecture
we have to understand this
the railways were created by the british
for the purpose of extracting wealth out
of india we know that
but the railways were created
with indian money with money the british
stole from india
they were built using indian labor
so it is indian money it is indian labor
so why do we call them the british
railways the british built them that but
why should we not use them it is our own
money and our own labor that gave rise
to these railways so it is ours it is
our it belongs to us it doesn't belong
to the british similarly all these big
buildings the british built the this
gothic architecture the so-called
indo-sarasanic architecture and the art
deco dances which is there in bombay
mumbai whatever
all of that was built by the british
again with indian money
and with indian labor
so why should we not use it
it belongs to us it belongs to the
people of india it was built with indian
money with indian labor please
understand that
the british did it but they did it with
indian money and indian labor so that's
why we should use it we should make use
of it it doesn't make us good or bad or
anything
we have to use what we have
that's it
bhagwan says you explained many things
about indian
way of style but democracy is itself
alien to india there were only emperors
and kings in the past
should whether please explain our views
on whether india should have a democracy
or an emperor democracy is being misused
by politicians as they are dividing
india
and people of india in many ways that
even the british couldn't divide in
these ways so please explain your views
yeah
so you are right india before the
british has always had
a
system of monarchy either emperors or
kings
and this western styled democracy is of
course something that is alien to india
i agree with you but india also had a
democratic system whether it is in the
mahajanapadas or even before that in
which you would have a centralized ruler
the emperor or the king but on at the
local level people would elect their own
officials and representatives
so whether it was the the village level
or the city level or the state level
it would all be done under the
supervision of the king or the emperor
but people would have self-rule india is
in fact the birthplace of a democracy
even western researchers have remarked
upon the fact that in the entire sindh
region in the indus
region whether you look at cities like
mohenjo-daro harappa or
piranha or any other smaller settlement
from that era you don't see a single
palace you don't see a single
such structure which indicates
aristocracy or royalty the most imposing
structures are always the
the assembly hall
or the bath house or the meeting hall so
these
were clearly systems that were not
uh tyrannical or there was no such uh
imperial system in this in this era
it was clearly some form of democracy
so that has been india's system it has
been a mixed system we have a country
a civilization state of the size of
india a
entire subcontinent
needs a very strong central
uh rule from one location so it needs
that so yes india that's why india
always had emperors and kings
but you also had democracy so it was a
mixed system now when it comes to
western style liberal democracy that we
are practicing today it is incredibly
counterproductive
for example we have this
anti-nationalism that proliferates
nowadays in the guise of free speech
you have a judiciary that is not
accountable to anybody it elects and
selects itself
in any other democratic country in the
world the judiciary
is
selected by the parliament or the
elected bodies of the of the country
it's only in india that the judiciary is
under no one's
oversight
so the judiciary in india is
unaccountable and so and so forth
india's democracy itself is incomplete
because within every single political
party there is no democracy
it is like a fiefdom
and that's why we every time you go for
the for voting it's always the four or
five same parties and same same people
so it's
so before
2014 people used to complain that you
always get the same four or five people
that you have to vote for so it's always
the choice between from between the the
worst of the worst so you have to
choose the person who is the least
evil
that sort of thing
so
democracy is incomplete because there is
no internal democracy within political
parties some political parties have a
better level of internal democracy but
the vast majority of political parties
in india are family run enterprises
there is no democracy within
so this system is actually it makes a
mockery of democracy and secondly if
if you want to actually stand for
election you don't stand a chance
because it it's all done on money unless
you have
several crore rupees to throw around
during your election campaign nobody
will even come to know about you and you
will definitely not not win the election
that's why independent candidates never
win elections and so on
so you are right that uh this western
style
fake liberal democracy is not suitable
for india
the westminster parliamentary system
that we have is something that evolved
on a small island in the atlantic ocean
it is not suited for a
subcontinent-sized civilization such as
india
that's why india needs reforms but the
political system that we have today is a
self-serving system the politicians
have come to power because of the system
they are beholden to the system
they are invested in the system and they
will not allow it to change so we are in
a conundrum today that's the problem so
i agree that this this system is not
good
for
the country in the long run
okay let me now take some
live chat questions i will take a few
live chat questions now
so if you have any questions that you
would like to ask me please ask me now
please talk about hyo huang oak the
indian princess who married a korean
prince it is said she was from the
ayuthiya kingdom which might be avidya
some say she was from kanyakumari i have
spoken about this in the past i there is
a small
video clipping on this channel in which
you can see that so
huang hak
huang ok is
an ancient korean queen
she
according to korean tradition she was
born in ayutthya in india she came to
korea she married married the local king
and she is the ancestor of many of a
significant percentage of the korean
population today
so her ancestral kingdom is called
ayuthiya which clearly is ayodhya there
can be no other name
some people say she was from kanyakumari
because because there is some fish
symbol etc
this nonsense has to stop
this is something that emerges from
tamil chauvinism some people claim that
because there is some fish symbol that's
why she was a south indian queen not a
north indian queen well tell me is there
any place called ayodhya in south india
there's none
so yeah that's that's what it is
she was from ayodhya
according to the to the
korean history itself according to the
version of history that they have she
was from ayutthya which is ayodhya that
is that their pronunciation of the word
ayodhya
so that's what we know about her her
tomb is there somewhere in korea
so
that in brief is about this ancient
connection between india and korea that
goes back about 2000 years before today
okay some more questions
if we make sanskrit the official
language some people will make it a
hindu muslim issue how do we deal with
that to deal with that we need good
leadership a strong leadership will deal
with any such issues
this entire hindu muslim nonsense it is
because india is so
weak and divided like i said if swashing
rabos had been the president or prime
minister or dictator of india none of
this hindu muslim nonsense would have
happened in this country everybody would
have been indian
and india would have slowly reverted to
its original state under somebody as
strong a leader
as him
so this
entire
situation we have today
so much division in the country it's
because of this fake
democracy we spoke about in which
freedom of speech becomes a fundamental
right and freedom of speech becomes
takes the guise of separatism and
internationalism
so india needs a genuinely strong
leader
that kind of leader unfortunately occur
emerges once in a thousand years but
that's what india needs again today
so we wait for a great leader
okay who what else do we have
how many temples did the turks destroyed
thousands maybe tens of thousands
uh there is a book by sitharam goel i
think
in which there is a list of temples that
have been destroyed
i think it's by sitharam goel i'm not
100 sure there was a book
i had seen a long time ago but the
number is definitely in the thousands or
or most likely in the tens of thousands
because there are still great temples
standing in southern india and there are
almost no
functional great temples in northern
india there are only ruins
so clearly these were in the tens of
thousands small big large etc
rishabh chaudhary says why is there no
fixed length of the yugas with the
present evidence twenty five thousand
nine twenty years it looks plausible
some people some theories suggest we are
deep into the ascending dwapper you go
see
there is a great deal of confusion about
what the yogas are and what is the
length of a yoga and all that some
people said that india is about 70
million years old and all i'm sorry
the earliest evidence of anatomically
modern human beings is about 200 250 000
years before today and those humans who
lived 250 000 years before today they
looked quite different from us
they had very prominent
uh rich rich bones and all that they
looked more like
archaic human beings
so if india is several lakh years old
then it it means that indians india has
existed basis before human times
so we need to
keep science scientific evidence in our
mind
i i don't know what is the calculation
of the yugas i don't know how it is
calculated clearly these calculations
that go back millions of years
are wrong
some so i i don't really know i am not
an expert in this subject i have not
studied everything in the world
but these fantastical claims that india
is several million years old these are
clearly nonsense
we have to first understand what science
is what science tells us
what scientific evidence tells us
so the to the best of our understanding
from the best evidence that we have
today
india was settled 70 000 or 65 000 years
before today
from the last out of africa migration
that is what i demonstrated in the first
of the first or second question itself
of this session
so
india is at the most
70 000 years old
human settlement modern human homo
sapiens settlement is about 70 000 years
old in india
india was the first founding zone
of the last out of africa migration
how can a yuga be millions of years old
and even this this evidence that you are
stating 25 000 something years old
i mean what is the evidence for this
who has come up with this with this
uh date or calculation
the problem is that these researchers i
mean they mean well
there are so many researchers amateur
researchers in india who are trying to
decipher our history because our
academics our trained academics are not
doing this so all these uh
untrained researchers amateur
researchers are trying to figure this
out and because they lack scientific
understanding etc they are coming up
with fantastical dates and all these
things
and this is adding to the confusion
instead of clarifying matters
so i think the yugas may have been much
shorter
than what these figures give us
maybe so according to some
interpretations by certain people we may
even be at the very end of the of the
kali yuga we may be
perhaps
soon going to transition into
a new satay yoga perhaps so i don't know
i have not studied this in any detail i
am not an expert in this but clearly
these fantastical
calculations are clearly wrong they
can't be right
adi shroud says did george mallory reach
the summit and die coming down we don't
know so you he's talking adish is
talking about the first one of the
first attempts to scale mount everest
sagar mata
mount everest is the colonial name of
this mountain it is either sagar mata or
chomologma in tibetan
so it was
irwin and mallory
ernest irvin and george mallory i think
two englishmen who tried to climb this
mountain i think in the 1930s if i'm not
mistaken i don't remember the exact
decade but yeah much before edmond
hillary and tenzing norgay
so
it seems there is some circumstantial
evidence that mallory may have
reached the summit and he died coming
down we know both died their bodies were
not found only i think only irwin's body
was found recently and one body is still
missing most likely mallory
so we don't have the evidence thus far
one of these guys took a camera with him
if we can find the camera we may be able
to
get some information whether they
actually took a photograph from the
summit or not
but it is definitely a possibility that
they may have submitted and they may
have died while coming down that's an
interesting ancient
reasonably ancient mystery
okay let me take one
last question for this session
okay who built the kutta miner because
there are many evidences of it being a
hindu structure it is one of these turks
uh who was it was it kathmandu
who built it most likely it is named
after khuttabal
al-din ibak
so most likely it was that guy that
turkic invader occupier who built this
but like you say
if you examine the structure itself
it is very clear that it's a hindu jain
structure so what happened was that in
the place where you have this qatar mina
today there was a temple complex i'm not
sure if it was a jain complex or a hindu
complex it's the same thing essentially
same culture
so this temple complex was destroyed by
these turks and the material
the bricks and the stones etc from these
temples they were repurposed
into building this tower structure this
kuthub minar so if you go to the place
and you examine it it's clear that these
stones they came from temples because
you have temple carvings and carvings of
gods and deities
on
the rocks in the stones of this
structure so it was built from material
taken from destroyed hindu or jain or
both temples
that is the short answer
okay i know you guys have lots of other
questions i could take another four
hours five hours but i think i will stop
for today
so thank you everybody for all your
questions great fun answering these
questions let let's continue having
these conversations
and i will see you
in the next session in the next week
until then take care thank you very much
have a good day have a good night